#### Contact

+380952841985 (Mobile) roman.kirilenko@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ romankirilenko (LinkedIn)

# Top Skills

Python (Programming Language)
Amazon Web Services (AWS)
docker

Languages

**English** 

#### Certifications

Learn Python 3 Course

Kubernetes: Cloud Native

Ecosystem

Learning Kubernetes

Lean Technology Strategy: Moving Fast With Defined Constraints

Kubernetes: Microservices

# Roman Kirilenko

Lead DevOps engineer at Anodot Ukraine

# Summary

Fast contact: https://romanki.github.io/

Long story:)

My long way with computers started from childhood, when my father brought me Old Russian PC, at that time I was six years old, and the computer became my favorite toy. In my life of IT, I've tried many of directions in this area, starting from Any-key and step-by-step growing in another kind of technologies, to 1stlevel support, 2nd-level support, network support engineer, system administrator, application support, infrastructure/development support, and others interesting jobs. In general, I'm always preferred support positions, but other skills like shell scripting and different programming languages I used only to improve support possibilities. I try to take a creative approach to work, I like to automate and optimize everything, I am an absolute perfectionist. I aspire to selfdevelopment in the field of information and telecommunication technologies, the main objective is to work in software Development Company and to be involved in the release and delivery of products. Have excellent knowledge of System Administration of the hardware and software levels, networks, operating systems of different types of OSes - Windows family, Linux RPM/Debian based and \*BSD. Knowledge and experience with Amazon Web Services (AWS). Specialties: Dev-Ops, System administration, networks administrating, application support, user support, development support, infrastructure support, release management, configuration management.

# Experience

Anodot Lead DevOps engineer November 2018 - Present (3 years 11 months) Kiev Region, Ukraine

## Responsibilities:

- develop on-premise installation scripts and processes for the product;
- integrate monitoring for the on-premise product;
- setup and configure Kubernetes cluster with product and dependencies considering on-premise policies, security requirements, different OSes, and datacenters;
- ci/cd, mostly Jenkins;
- benchmarking analysis, load testing, crash-testing;
- working with RnD and Dev, QA, DevOps teams, mostly scrum;

Technologies and tools to work within the project:

- AWS
- GCP
- DO
- Terraform
- Docker
- etcd
- Kubernetes
- Kubespray
- Helm
- Prometheus
- Grafana
- ELK/EFK
- Jenkins
- Jira
- Git
- GitHub Actions;
- Java

App dependencies inside k8s:

- Kafka
- Cassandra
- Elasticsearch
- MongoDB
- Postgres
- Apache Spark
- NFS for k8s

Playtech

6 years 1 month

Product operations team leader

January 2014 - October 2018 (4 years 10 months) Kiev

Manage team of product operations and deployment engineers.

Product Operation Engineer October 2012 - January 2014 (1 year 4 months) Kiev

Release and deployment procedures

- Obtaining and configuring environments
- Configuring access to any kind of environments
- · Continuous integration configuring
- Continuous delivery configuring
- Source code management system setup and administration

Automation of project build procedures

- Configuring build tasks manual builds, testing builds, release builds, nightly builds for reporting (with Sonar for example)
- Writing scripts for to automate uncommon situations (Ex. Clear JMS Queues before and after deploying new version of application, through JMX from shell) Delivery and deployment processes
- Make decisions by which protocol to deliver applications in different situations.
- Configure network accesses for different protocols
- Writing scripts to automate transferring of applications to different environments.

Products support

- Do manual/automated checks after application deployment, for any kind of exceptions, errors, warnings etc.
- Issues solving produced by QA or 1st level reports
   Infrastructure tools and services maintenance
- Full emulation of production environment with many dependencies and services, like external JMS, DB, Quartz Scheduler, Fail-over and many other things which is needed for development and to successfully start application, prepare it for testing locally or for a QA teams.

Development team support

- Test environments setup and configuring, like Linux boxes with configured Tomcat, or Weblogic for example.
- Preparing, setup and configuring development environments
- Setup and configuring monitoring systems, for to be able to monitor and gather stats of any kind of instances (JMX, Databases, OS and other services).

#### Luxoft

2 years 2 months

Configuration Manager

August 2011 - October 2012 (1 year 3 months)

Kiev, Ukraine

Release and deployment procedures

- Setup and configure CI servers
- · Configure build tasks
- · Configure continuous delivery and deployment

Automation to build project processes

- Configure automated build tasks
- Automate deployment to any kind of environments

Product support and maintenance

· Application issues solving, like configurations, networking, etc.

Infrastructure tools and services maintenance

- Setup and configure dependencies for application
- Different kind of development tools
- Additional services, like wiki, internal chats, internal documentation sharing
   Development team support
- · Development environments setup and configure
- Networking configurations, requesting firewall accesses
- Local development issues solving.

Infrastructure Coordinator

September 2010 - August 2011 (1 year)

Support local and remote development teams

- Creating appropriate requests for both sides to get connected to each other for development teams cross countries.
- Setup development environments
- Request firewall accesses
- Troubleshooting networking and local issues
- Setup, configure and resolving connectivity issues
- RSA Tokens requesting and configuring
- Networking issues solving
- Working directly with foreign support teams over many other countries.
- Collaborate on cross networking tasks, for example when application needs
  to get data from database which placed in New York and put it to DB in
  London. So it is needed to get connected with different firewall teams, DBAs,
  Program managers and clarify all questions to get successfully way to flow
  data traffic.

# Dessange International (Kiev, Ukraine)

IT Manager

April 2010 - September 2010 (6 months)

Organization and support of IT infrastructure of the company and remote offices in Kiev, Ukraine.

# **IT&T** Consulting

Specialist Support

October 2009 - June 2010 (9 months)

- \* Night and day duty
- \* Monitoring of services and servers
- \* Creation of reports, establishment ticket on the issues identified
- \* Working with Nagios, Cacti, Jira

#### Adamant

**Specialist Support** 

September 2009 - February 2010 (6 months)

Users support, identification and removal of telecommunication problems, network administration, LAN VLAN, xDSL, based on \*nix servers.

# Vogster Entertainment

1 year 7 months

Game Designer

June 2008 - March 2009 (10 months)

Game Designer

#### **QA** Tester

September 2007 - June 2008 (10 months)

Conducted manual testing of games - Crime Craft and others.

## djuice-club

Administrator \ System Administrator

September 2006 - September 2007 (1 year 1 month)

Public Computer Club, in which I served as Administrator \ System Administrator

# Education

Kiivs'kij Slavisticnij Universitet